GREGORY DAMIANI

gregory.damiani@gmail.com
https://github.com/grggls/
https://uk.linkedin.com/in/gregorydamiani
https://twitter.com/grggls

I require a visa/sponsorship to work outside the US

Senior Systems Engineer with experience leading teams, planning and executing agile projects, coding infrastructures, maintaining performance, security, fault-tolerance and overall system health. Desired roles include senior-level site reliability engineer, devops engineer, operations engineer, AWS architect, and infrastructure engineer. I'm also interested in interviewing for engineering manager roles.

Working with developers, product, management, and customers, I've spent almost twenty years building and maintaining stable systems in mission-critical, high-traffic environments. Believing the whole engineering staff should be empowered and responsible for system health, customer experience, and the speed with which experiments are conducted and features delivered is at the heart of not only my work but the way it's communicated and shared.

Research interests include Data, Crypto, Sustainability, Agtech, IoT, Renewable Energy, Sharing Economies

CERTIFICATIONS

- Google Certified Professional Cloud Architect
- Amazon Web Services Certified Systems Architect Associate Level
- Certified Chef Developer

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Aluna Social, London October 2017 to present

— Working part-time with an early stage crypto startup to secure and stabilise infrastructure, build and maintain a Kube cluster, deploy microservices there, develop and increase the velocity of their development pipeline

Cloudreach Europe Ltd., London
Cloud Systems Developer Lead - July 2017 to present

- Leading a team of developers to deliver AWS infrastructure and automation for data ingestion and financial analysis
- Providing excellent customer support and training for our clients around the Cloud Data Center we have implemented
- Mentoring several juniors and coaching them towards AWS certification
- Developing system services in Python

BuzzFeed, Inc., New York and London

Senior Site Reliability Engineer - January 2014 to July 2017

- Applied Lean Startup techniques to systems and operations tool-smithing, Agile and TDD
- Empowered developers to deploy and test using a homegrown Docker PaaS, contributing code, testing, and day-to-day administration of the infrastructure
- Built systems for CI/CD of configuration management code, reducing outages and issues caused by misconfiguration company-wide and standardized development environments
- Lead engineering projects and evangelized SRE tenets for fault tolerance and recoverability
- Developing microservices in Python: monitoring and verification scripts, AWS management tools, as well as Ansible modules.
- Used AWS, GCP, Docker, ECS, Jenkins, Chef, Ansible, Puppet, Nagios, Datadog, ELK, Terraform, CloudFormation, Vault

2u, Inc. (formerly 2tor, Inc.), New York Devops Engineer – May 2012 to January 2014

- Engineered a full-stack configuration tool/CLI using CloudFormation, Puppet, and Python
- Enabled SaaS-like deployment of our main offerings for all new university partners
- Built a multi-tenant system for testing new code on Staging environments 30-40 times a day
- Mentored two interns with little experience to become root-wielding administrators
- Grew from sole administrator of a large AWS infrastructure to managing a small team

National September 11 Memorial and Museum, New York, NY Linux System Administrator – June 2011 to May 2012

- Met strict deadlines ahead of global launch on 11 September 2011
- Built auto-scaling web infrastructure to handle spiky load
- Virtualized infrastructure on a number of clouds/platforms including AWS and VMware ESXi
- Built deploy automation and configuration management with Chef for all Linux servers

Discopedia, New York, NY

Founder, Principal Engineer, Software Developer June 2010 to April 2011

— Designed and developed twitter and wikipedia graph walking software in PHP and Java. Product management. Bare-bones operations.

TradingScreen, New York, NY
Infrastructure Engineer April 2008 to May 2010

- Installed and operated multiple data centres. Rack, stack, cable, and configure.
- Resolved outage conditions during on-call rotations and change management windows

California State University, Hayward, CA Operating Systems Engineer August 2006 to June 2007

Inherited a 30 year old datacentre with little handoff or documentation. Discovery, stabilization, documentation, remediation.

JP Morgan Chase, Jersey City, NJ Project Manager May 2004 to June 2006

— Managed projects of increasing complexity, working with teams of up to 25 engineers to discover and remediate data centres and systems as well as reduce global IT spend by \$2 million annually.

University of Michigan Engineering Research Center, Ann Arbor, MI Research Analyst June 1999 to June 2002

— Developed control system software in Java for reconfigurable manufacturing machines.

EDUCATION

New York University, New York, NY Certificate in International Affairs, July 2010 to September 2010

— Focus on emerging economies, political economy, and sustainable development

Institute of Industrial Technology and Automation, Milan, Italy Masters in Industrial Research, June 2002 to December 2003

- Recipient of an Italian government fellowship to study and research
- Thesis: "Software and Methods for Life Cycle Cost Accounting of Reconfigurable Manufacturing Machines"

University of Michigan College of Engineering, Ann Arbor, MI Bachelor of Engineering, September 1998 to April 2002

— Major: Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

KEYWORD SOUP

AWS, GCP, Python, Ruby, Chef, Puppet, Ansible, CloudFormation, Terraform, Docker, Configuration Management, CI/CD, TDD, TDI, Nagios, DataDog, New Relic, Splunk, Prometheus